# Laura Barrera Martinez

206-899-6651 | larmartinez2@gmail.com | GitHub: github.com/lauramartinezdev | linkedin.com/in/lauramartinezdev/

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Proactive and self-motivated Software Development Engineer with 5 years of experience, including a strong background in AWS, Python, and REST APIs development. Strong communication and collaboration skills. Able to work independently and learn new concepts quickly. Actively promotes a culture of collaboration and learning through mentoring and knowledge sharing.

**TECHNICAL SKILLS:** Python | Ruby | React | JavaScript | Java | Terraform | HTML + CSS | AWS | Git | React | Node | Agile TDD | Unit Tests | E2E Tests | Development Lifecycle | REST

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Software Development Engineer | Zillow

08/2019 - 02/2024

# Software Development Engineer Intern | Zillow

02/2019 - 07/2019

Real-estate marketplace company with 226 million users

- Provided technical advice, leadership, and direction on software engineering projects.
- Developed and maintained multiple AWS Lambda to support backend functionalities.
- Wrote high-quality, performant, well-tested and well- documented Python, Java and Javascript code.
- Triggered surveys and updated databases based on an event-driven architecture using big data systems, analytics, containerized microservices, serverless functions, and queues in AWS.
- Pioneered the process for storing values in AWS parameter Store and how to set up permissions using terraform.
- Ensured exceptional customer service by addressing inquiries and technical issues from partner teams, fostering seamless collaboration.

### Software Engineering Student | Ada Developers Academy

01/2018 - 01/2019

Software Engineering Apprenticeship with an 8% acceptance rate

- Studied full-stack software engineering in an intensive, project-based, and highly selective program.
- Ability to learn extremely quickly by completing twenty-four non-trivial coding projects in six months.
- Developed an e-commerce site in collaboration with a team, implementing shopping cart and checkout features to ensure a seamless user experience.

## Data Analyst | Data2insight

07/2017 - 12/2017

Data Science firm that helps businesses, government agencies, and universities make meaningful impact.

- Intern turned contractor. Analyzed and consolidated data from diverse origins, ensuring data quality.
- Developed Python scripts for statistical analysis and data visualization using libraries such as NumPy and Matplotlib.
- Sorted and analyzed data using Excel Pivot Tables and effectively communicated technical findings to stakeholders.

#### Research Technician | University of Zurich and University of Washington Medical Center

02/2013 - 12/2016

Research center for the study of the human brain in health and disease.

- Utilized Python, R, and Matlab to process neuroimaging data for the Seattle Longitudinal Study.
- Presented research at national conferences.
- Received 1 of 27 research grants from the Embassy of Switzerland to facilitate the adaptation of the Seattle Longitudinal Study data processing pipeline to a new lab in Zurich.

## **EDUCATION**

## University of Washington, Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Physics, March 2015

CSE Courses: Data Structures and Algorithms, Computer Science Fundamentals, Introduction to R for Data Analysis.

### Ada Developers Academy, Computer Science, June 2019

CSE Courses: Ruby, Rails, Javascript, HTML, CSS, GitHub, OOP and TDD, CS Fundamentals, Agile Development.

Capstone Project: Developed an iOS mobile app in 3 weeks that tracks expiration date of items using a barcode reader and reminders. <a href="https://github.com/lauramar6261/capstone\_ReactNative">https://github.com/lauramar6261/capstone\_ReactNative</a> (React Native, Expo, Ruby on Rails, UPCitemdb API)